<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ghezae Fisseha</title>
    <link>https://gafstar.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ghezae Fisseha</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:03:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gafstar.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A/B Test Sample Size Calculation</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/22/a/b-test-sample-size-calculation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 08:03:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/22/a/b-test-sample-size-calculation/</guid>
      <description>
When designing an A/B test, it is imperative that we calculate the sample size.
With the help of online calculators or softwares, we can easily calculate the
sample size by filling in the significance level α, power (1-β), baseline value,
minimum detectable effect or margin of error. This becomes handy as we don’t
need to manually calculate the sample size ourselves. However, it might help to
understand what the assumptions are, so that we can trust the outcome of the
online calculators.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Cohort Analysis?</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/22/what-is-cohort-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/22/what-is-cohort-analysis/</guid>
      <description>
First, let&#39;s begin by defining what cohort mean. The word cohort is derived from
Latin cohors meaning an enclosure or enclosed group. In digital analytics
context it means a group of customers that share something in common. This
refers to a groupo of users who have similar characteristics or experiences
within a defined time-span. Therefore, cohort analysis is a type of behavioral
analytics that breaks the dataset into groups before conducting analysis.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Step by Step Machine Learning Approach on Portguese Bank Marketing Strategy</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/01/a-step-by-step-machine-learning-approach-on-portguese-bank-marketing-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/01/a-step-by-step-machine-learning-approach-on-portguese-bank-marketing-strategy/</guid>
      <description>
This data comes from UCI Machine Learning Repository. From analyzing this data,
I believe there are some insights that can be applied to other companies
strategy in acquiring new clients. The data is related with direct telemarketing
campaigns of a Portuguese banking institution. The marketing campaigns were
based on phone calls. Often, more than one contact to the same client was
required, in order to access if the phone call will result for a long term
deposit or not. This analysis is based only on 10% of the overall dataset used
by S. Moro et al., 2014.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Missing Values</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/01/handling-missing-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/06/01/handling-missing-values/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Missing values ​​are difficult to deal with, and there is no better way to deal with them. It depends on different scenarios that are random and in some cases nonrandom to the data. First, let us have a clear understanding of what we mean by missingness in data.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Binary Classification Using XGBoost</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/05/27/binary-classification-using-xgboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/05/27/binary-classification-using-xgboost/</guid>
      <description>
The purpose of this post it to understand how to apply XGBoost to a binary
classification problem. In this post we are going to see how to apply XGBoost
classifier algorithm to an adult data set downloaded from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/adult&#34;
  &gt;UCI Machine Learning Repository&lt;/a
&gt;. XGBoost is an optimized gradient boosting open source library knows for its
flexibility and portability. It is also a popular algorithm for machine learning
competitions for structured or tabular dataset. In
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/&#34;&gt;Kaggle competitions,&lt;/a&gt; it is the number one
choice for tabular dataset.

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Beautiful Dashboards</title>
      <link>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/05/27/creating-beautiful-dashboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gafstar.github.io/2021/05/27/creating-beautiful-dashboards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As a data analyst, I often create dashboards as part of my analysis. When supporting multiple stakeholders it might become quite tricky to design a dashboard that will serve all of them. Unfortunately, there is no one-size-fits-all solution when creating dashboards for multiple stakeholders. In this post, I will introduce some of the methods I use when designing self-serve dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
